Guide to the Doris Duke Foundation records, 1934-2009 (bulk 1948-1982)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Records, 1949-2001
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions. Includes Federal Tax Return, 1982 (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions. Includes Federal Tax Return, 1982 (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1980 (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1980 (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Contributions, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Grant requests to The Doris Duke Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Grant requests to The Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 Mar-Apr (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Grant requests to The Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 May (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Grant requests to The Doris Duke Foundation, 1996 Jun (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Grant requests to The Doris Duke Foundation, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Foundation grant request from the Foundation for Research of the New York Academy of Osteopathy, Inc., 1956 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Thank you letter from Boys Harbor, Inc. regarding $5,000 donation, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding St. Joseph Figure Skating Club, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda requesting donations, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding solicitation for donation to the Boys & Girls Club of Morris County, 1994 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Robert Duckmeir of the Doris Duke Foundation regarding donations made to Working Playground, Inc. and Historic House Truset of New York City, 1995, 1999 (Box 105, Folder 6)
- Financial Records, 1934-1996
  The Financial Records series contains a wide assortment of records related to the daily financial operations of the Doris Duke Foundation. Materials included are financial statements, annual reports of the DDF, journals and general ledgers, correspondence and other related materials regarding the financial status of the DDF.
  The materials are loosely arranged in chronological order.
  - Financial Statement, June 1934–December 1951 (2 of which are bound and embossed with DD) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Financial Statement, December 1951–December 1952 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Biennial Report, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Journal & General Ledger, 1971–1984 (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Journal & General Ledger, 1971–1984 (2 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - General Ledger I, 1968–1971 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - General Ledger IV, 1979–1981 (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - General Ledger IV, 1979–1981 (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - General Journal, 1985–1993 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Cashbook, receipts and disbursements, 1971–1984 (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Cashbook, receipts and disbursements, 1971–1984 (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Journal III, 1979–1981 (1 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Journal III, 1979–1981 (2 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Journal III, 1979–1981 (3 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Cashbook & Journal, 1966–1970 (Box 20)
  - General Ledger, 1966–1971 (Box 20)
  - General Ledger No. 5, 1955–1966 (Oversize-box 21)
  - Cashbook No. 5, 1955–1966 (Oversize-box 21)
  - Journal No. 5, 1955–1966 (Oversize-box 21)
  - General Ledger, 1971–1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1985–1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - New York State Taxes - Doris Duke Foundation, 1941-1957 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1988 Jun 30 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Doris Duke Foundation regarding trial balances and financial statements. Includes a checkbook from La Banque Continentale, 1957 and undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Bond Receipts and Stock Receipts, 1952-1969 (1 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Bond Receipts and Stock Receipts, 1952-1969 (2 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Bond Receipts and Stock Receipts, 1952-1969 (3 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Bond Receipts and Stock Receipts, 1952-1969 (4 of 4) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Special Account No. 2, 1956-1959 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Special Account No. 2, 1960-1962 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Special Account No. 2, 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Special Account No. 2, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Special Account No. 2, 1968-1971 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Statement of Changes in Fund Principal, 1967-1972 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - Securities Sold, 1956-1964 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Balance Sheet, 1975 Mar 31 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Cash Statements, 1960-1966 (1 of 2) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Cash Statements, 1960-1966 (2 of 2) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding the sale and purchase of United States Treasury Bills for the Doris Duke Foundation, 1963-1970 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding the sale and purchase of stock for the Doris Duke Foundation, 1957-1971 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - Credit advice from Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1972-1975 (1 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - Credit advice from Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1972-1975 (2 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - Credit advice from Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1972-1975 (3 of 3) (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Balance Statements with Goldman, Sachs & Co., 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Financial Statements, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial matters of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1952-1969 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1973-1975 (1 of 2) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1973-1975 (2 of 2) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Samples of letters to Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1961-1969 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - Summaries of donations and expenses, 1970-1974 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1971 (1 of 2) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1971 (2 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1972 (1 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1972 (2 of 2) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1960-1967 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and other related materials regarding financial status of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1973, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Donations, 1970-1977 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Checks paid by the Doris Duke Foundation, 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke Foundation, New York State Registration of Charitable Foundation Form NYCF-2, 1937-1963 (1 of 2) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Doris Duke Foundation, New York State Registration of Charitable Foundation Form NYCF-2, 1937-1963 (2 of 2) (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Doris Duke Foundation, New York State Registration of Charitable Foundation Form NYCF-2, 1965-1974 (1 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Doris Duke Foundation, New York State Registration of Charitable Foundation Form NYCF-2, 1965-1974 (2 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Foundation, New York State Registration of Charitable Foundation Form NYCF-2, 1965-1974 (3 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Financial Statements, 1950-1961, 1967-1974 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1989 (1 of 2) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1989 (2 of 2) (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - DDF Federal Tax Return, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1963-1965 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - DDF Tax Returns, 1960-1962 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - DDF IRS Tax Returns, 1950-1959 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - DDF IRS Tax Returns Current Work File, 1961-1969 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - DDF Accounting Documents, 1969-1974 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - DDF City of New York Taxes, 1971-1975 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and notices regarding DDF IRS return filings and tax exempt status, 1953-1975 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - DDF Federal Taxes, 1953, 1967, 1970-1975 (1 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - DDF Federal Taxes, 1953, 1967, 1970-1975 (2 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - DDF Tax Return, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - DDF State of New York Taxes, 1968-1976 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - DDF IRS Tax Returns, 1938-1949 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - DDF Audit, 1964-1968 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - DDF U.S. Old Age Pension & Withheld Tax Returns and correspondence, 1943 (1 of 3) (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - DDF U.S. Old Age Pension & Withheld Tax Returns and correspondence, 1943 (2 of 3) (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - DDF U.S. Old Age Pension & Withheld Tax Returns and correspondence, 1943 (3 of 3) (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - DDF New York City Income Tax, 1966-1970 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - DDF U.S. Old Age Pension & Federal Income Taxes, 1943-1959 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - DDF File copies of correspondence, 1968-1975 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - DDF Special Acct. #2, 1976-1980 (1 of 3) (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - DDF Special Acct. #2, 1976-1980 (2 of 3) (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - DDF Special Acct. #2, 1976-1980 (3 of 3) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Chemical Bank Statements, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - DDF Bank Statements and Transaction Summaries, Acct. #1, 1981-1986 (1 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - DDF Bank Statements and Transaction Summaries, Acct. #1, 1981-1986 (2 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - DDF Bank Statements and Transaction Summaries, Acct. #2, 1981-1986 (1 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - DDF Bank Statements and Transaction Summaries, Acct. #2, 1981-1986 (2 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - DDF Bank Accounts - Security Deposit Account, 1976-1981 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Bank Statements, 1979-1984 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Financial Statements, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation correspondence and financial worksheets, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation correspondence and financial worksheets, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation correspondence and financial worksheets, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - rent notices to Mr. Dana, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Foundation - General paid bills, 1975-1976 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Doris Duke Foundation - paid bills and copies of sub lease checks, 1977-1979 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke Foundation paid bills - insurance miscellaneous, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation paid bills, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Forms, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial statements, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF Form (Tax Return), 1981 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Forms, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF Form (Tax Return), 1984 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF Form (Tax Return), 1982-1983 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - State of Delaware Franchise Tax Reports, 1972-1996 (1 of 2) (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - State of Delaware Franchise Tax Reports, 1972-1996 (2 of 2) (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Reports, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Donation of Assets, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Reports, Year end statement, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Reports, Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Reports, Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation 990PF and 990AR Reports, Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Tax Returns and correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Tax Return, 1985 (1 of 2) (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Tax Return, 1985 (2 of 2) (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation Tax Return, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Annual Reports and Tax Returns, 1970-1974 (1 of 2) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Doris Duke Foundation Annual Reports and Tax Returns, 1970-1974 (2 of 2) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation financial worksheets and correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 37, Folder 3)
- Subject Files, 1934-2009
  The Subject Files series primarily documents the donating activities of the Doris Duke Foundation, including incoming correspondence from various non-profit organizations soliciting donations, donations that were granted, and donation requests that were denied. This series illustrates the transition of the foundation from Independent Aid, Inc. to the Doris Duke Foundation, in particular documenting the foundation's changing philanthropic interests. In addition to correspondence, the files often contain clippings, proof of tax exemption status, treasurer’s receipts, review sheets, photographs, reports and proposals, annual reports, pamphlets, and other promotional material.
  The “Closed Files” and “Current Files” appear to have been maintained at the same time. When an organization was no longer under consideration or receiving donations they were removed from the “Current File” to the “Closed File.” Both appear to have been maintained until around 1975, although some later material can be found in the files.
  Files regarding the staff and Board of the DDF are also included amongst the various correspondence files. W.C. Davison, Duke University Medical Center Dean and Vice President of the Board of Trustees, is featured prominently in the series, often advocating aid to various healthcare related causes, especially in North Carolina. Additional files on Georgea T. Furst (Includes correspondence with Doris Duke regarding travels abroad with birth control activist Margaret Sanger), Clarence E. Pickett (Board President until 1957), C.D. Jackson (Board Member), John M. Schiff (Board Member), Sophia van Theis (Executive Secretary-Treasurer and Board Member), Leta McBean (Board Member, began serving under her maiden name McDonald), Michael Chinigo (consultant), Lloyd A. Pantages (Board Member) and the Duke Office provide insight into the administration of the DDF.
  Grants-In-Aid, Scholarships are records of individual scholarships awarded by Independent Aid, Inc. and the Doris Duke Foundation. These grants were issued between 1937 and 1959, with an additional grant being awarded in 1967. Included in the first folder are photocopies of the original folders listing each scholarship recipient by year. Unlike the rest of the Closed Files subseries these files were not arranged alphabetically, but instead were placed at the end of the series by the records’ creators.
  1975 Denials contain a record of organizations that were denied aid. In addition to denials from 1975, denials from as early as 1951 were kept interfiled within this subseries. 1976 and 1977 Denials contain aid rejections from their respective calendar years. The 1975 Denials were most likely maintained at the DDF New York Office by May E. McFarland, while the later Denials were maintained by Elisabeth McConville at the N.J. Residence.
  The Miscellaneous Donation Files were created by combining all donation materials which were not included in the previous categories, i.e., some files were foldered and labeled, some unlabeled, and others were found loose in the drawers. Of particular interest are the May E. McFarland files which contain correspondence from Doris Duke's Personal Fund and donations to Negro Colleges in the 1960s and 1970s.
  Arrangement Note: All Subject Files are arranged in the order in which they were found. For the most part, they are arranged alphabetically, with the exception of the Miscellaneous Donation Files which were arranged in the order in which they were found.
  RESTRICTED: Access to folders in boxes 103 and 104 are restricted and require prior written approval from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation to view.
  - Aleppo College: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1953–1957 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the United Nations: Donations, Closed Files, 1955–1957 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - American Correctional Association: Donations, Closed Files, 1953–1956 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - American Economic Foundation: Donations, Closed Files, 1957–1972 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - American Farm School: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1953–1974 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - American Foundation for Overseas Blind: Donations, Closed Files, 1952–1959 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - American Friends of the Middle East: Donations, Closed Files. Includes 1952 City of New York tax exemption, 1952–1958 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - American Friends Service Committee: Donations, Closed Files. Includes clipping, 1957–1970 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - American Friends Service Committee – Projects: Indian, Salvador, Korea, and Italy: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1949–1957 (1 of 2) (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - American Friends Service Committee – Projects: Indian, Salvador, Korea, and Italy: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1949–1957 (2 of 2) (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - American Korea Foundation: Donations, Closed Files, 1954–1962 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - American Joint Committee for Assisting Japanese American Orphans: Donations, Closed Files, 1953–1957 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - American Leprosy Missions: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photograph and 1955 tax exemption, 1955–1966 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - American Public Health Association: Donations, Closed Files, 1955–1960 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - American Public Welfare Association: Donations, Closed Files, 1950–1962 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - American University of Beirut: Donations, Closed Files, 1954–1964 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - American Youth Hostels: Donations, Closed Files, 1947–1958 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - A.R.R.O.W. – National Congress of American Indians: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1954–1971 (1 of 2) (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - A.R.R.O.W. – National Congress of American Indians: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1954–1971 (2 of 2) (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children: Donations, Closed Files, 1958–1968 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Indian Affairs: Donations, Closed Files, 1938, 1954–1957 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo – Sergei Denham: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1943–1950 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Bank Street College of Education: Donations, Closed Files, 1949–1973 (1 of 2) (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Bank Street College of Education: Donations, Closed Files, 1949–1973 (2 of 2) (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Banks, Bertram: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1944–1962 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Barnard College – Mrs. McIntosh: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1939–1953, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Bentick, Mrs. Morris: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1945–1951 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Berea College – Berea, Kentucky: Donations, Closed Files. Includes clippings, 1950–1967 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Berkshire Industrial Farm: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photograph and clippings, 1952–1962 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Big Brothers: Donations, Closed Files. Includes clippings, 1951–1963 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Bio-Sciences Information Exchange: Donations, Closed Files, 1953–1959 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Blinded Veterans of Southern California: Donations, Closed Files. Includes clippings and 1955 tax exemption, 1953–1963 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Boys’ Clubs of Newport County: Donations, Closed Files. Includes 1958 tax exemption, 1959–1965 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Juveniles Guidance Center: Donations, Closed Files. Includes clippings and correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1950–1960 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Brown Folk Lore Collection – Duke University: Donations, Closed Files. Includes clipping and correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1948–1958 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - C.A.R.E. – Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe, Inc.: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1950–1952 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - California Paralyzed Veterans Association: Donations, Closed Files. Includes 1947 tax exemption, 1953–1960 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - California Paralyzed Veterans Association – Dr. Elwell, Research: Donations, Closed Files, 1959–1962 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Carrie Chapman Catt: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1951–1961 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Child Study Association of America: Donations, Closed Files, 1952–1953 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Child Welfare League of America: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photograph, 1958 and 1967 tax exemptions, and correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1949–1969 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - The Childrens’ Aid Society: Donations, Closed Files, 1963–1968 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Children’s Bureau (H.E.W.) – Special Juvenile Delinquency Project: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1952–1957 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Children’s Home Society of California: Donations, Closed Files, 1955–1959 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Children’s Home Society of North Carolina: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1950–1953 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Children’s Medical Center – Philippines: Donations, Closed Files. Includes photographs, 1964–1973 (Box 42, Folder 9)